(chime)
(tapping)
(silence)
(chime)
Hey, how's it going?
Hey, let me give my mics quick.
All right, sick.
I'm not gonna turn my camera on
because my room's kinda messy.
Do you wanna tell me about the script I just made?
Oh, sure, sure.
Yeah, so pretty much.
It just automatically goes into one dataset.
Let me show you how it works.
I made a log for it as well.
The command is just autocollect.
Okay, we got a note taker in here, just so you know.
How's your day, Ben?
Oh, pretty good.
Yeah, I got a little bit of work done
revising the draft of the paper,
and then I saw that new film called Project Hail Mary.
Nice.
It was all right.
I thought it was interesting.
It's kind of like they took the idea for Interstellar,
but then they were more optimistic with it.
Oh, okay.
I never watched Interstellar.
What was it about?
There's this fungus that destroys
all the world's crops except for corn,
so it causes a bunch of problems.
Matthew McConaughey is asked by NASA
to go into a wormhole
and check out some planets to migrate to.
Oh, okay.
That's pretty cool.
It's pretty good.
It's more of a story about his
relationship with his daughter,
but it's pretty good.
Very touching film.
Can I ask you a quick question?
Sure, absolutely.
Hi, Tion, you?
Hello.
I'm available today.
Yeah, so are you discussing the code?
Oh, yeah.
Maxwell was just about to show me a script
that he made for the croissant format.
I see.
I was just wondering how was
the current progress of the paper?
If anything, I could contribute,
or if there's any progress?
Yeah, I made two different revisions
because I sent the paper to somebody
and they pointed out that one of the claims in the paper
that we're doing the first Monte Carlo tree system
in latent space for adversarial evaluation.
They said that we should make sure that that's true.
So I looked into it some more,
and it's not entirely true.
It's been done before,
but we're doing it in a unique
way that hasn't been tried before.
So I revised that section of the paper.
I'll send you a link now of the most updated version.
It contains several notes.
So I was hoping for your input on those
as well as how we justify the first experiments.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, sure.
Other than that, it hasn't changed too much.
Let's see.
But yeah, Maxwell, or Max, sorry.
Yeah, I just had a real quick.
So this is a tremendous.
So it just automatically goes to dataset
and the docs folder.
It runs for a little bit.
Sure.
Oh, nice.
I just thought I could hold artifacts
and put it in 2.4.
Yep, yep.
Max tokens, that's good.
Max tokens in MathLink.
Okay, I'll look into that.
Max tokens will take precedence.
Okay. So I'm going to do that. Okay, and it's loading the H-neuron monitor from that paper.
I'm going to take note of that discrepancy in the script.
I must have set both of the variables to Max
and it's prioritizing token length.
Or new tokens, sorry.
But it must still be running.
Oh, yeah, I know.
So it's going to go 10 times then, huh?
I guess it's just spitting out that line
and it generates a new example.
Yeah.
Calibration complete.
Okay, so it's identified 50 H-neurons.
Just let me know if anything looks bad or just...
I think it seems to be running well.
It's only spitting out a slight error,
which isn't, you know, it's not
interfering with the experiment.
It's just annoying to see it constantly spit it out.
But I don't think that's your fault.
I think it's okay.
Well, that runs.
I have to message a teammate.
They're having trouble getting into the meeting.
Okay, they're having...
Right.
In the meantime, I'll pull up that paper.
I don't want to waste any time here.
Yeah.
Oh, that should be deep D.
I just ended...
Hello, Josh.
Hello, Josh. Hello, Josh. This is deep D.
Hello.
Hello, deep D.
Good evening.
Good evening. Good to hear from you.
We're actually running a test of Max's new script
for storing the data in the first experiment
on the one billion parameter model.
Tiny Llama.
Oh, I see.
Wow.
Max.
Hello, Max.
Hey, how you doing?
I'm good.
I haven't met you before, I think.
So greetings from me.
I'm based in Georgia.
Oh, you are?
Yeah, deep D is a data scientist.
Sorry, deep D is a data scientist.
And I met her in the early stages
of the first phase of the Agent Meets competition.
So she's been...
Nice as hell.
Yeah, she's provided some really great insight
about some of the ideas that we've been working on
in the project and the whole concept
for what we ended up doing for phase one.
So it was really helpful to have her feedback.
Thank you, Josh. Yeah.
So let's see here.
I'm gonna stop sharing, but does it look good too?
Yeah, this looks great.
So, and then I'm assuming...
Where is it exporting to?
Just a data assessment.
Oh, okay, in the CSV?
Yeah.
Okay, perfect.
Okay, okay.
Great, yeah. And then, did you know what specific format?
Of course not, because I was looking over the handbook
for NUR IPS and they specify a specific one,
but I don't think it should be too much of an issue.
It should be easy to adapt.
I was just wondering if you...
It should be a specific one.
I'm pretty sure I just ran the one that was...
It was the same here because this data set already existed.
So if it was on the repo, then it should be okay.
But I can just check one more
time before I make up the art for it.
Okay, sweet.
Yeah, I'll give you any info you may need for that.
There's a link to the handbook,
so I'll find the specifications.
Okay, almost done uploading this paper here,
and then I'll put the link in the Google chat.
Okay, here we go.
Okay, share.
Copy.
Okay, here's the new version.
So one of the things I did was I updated it to the format
that they require for submission.
There were several things that I learned in the handbook.
One thing is that they have
their own STY file for every year.
And then I think there were
some other formatting requirements
that had to do with page numbers
and just simple stuff like that.
But I was wondering, like, Tion, I have a question.
Have you reviewed the handbook for NERIPS submission,
and have you submitted to them in the past?
I just wanted to know your
familiarity with this organization.
Tion, you?
Oh, did he leave?
Yeah, I think he left.
Oh, no.
He's taking the notes, right?
Wildfly.ai.
Let me see if I can get him back in here,
because I need him to answer that question.
Did he mention that he was leaving?
Maybe he left by accident.
[typing]
Okay, maybe we...
Okay, I'm not sure what happened.
Maybe he thought it wasn't the best time to check in.
Okay, who here has read over the paper
so that we can quickly review
it if he's going to come back in?
Has anybody in here read the paper yet?
It's okay if you haven't.
We can just overview it from a high level,
but I need honest answers so that I
can provide the information for you guys.
I will read it by tomorrow.
I was going to, but I didn't get time.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
So if you're pressed on time, I
recommend taking the text file,
just plugging it into your favorite large language model
and having it give you some bullet
points about what it boils down to.
So just take it, put it into Gemini,
and then you'll get just a high level overview of it.
In the meantime, I'm going to cover some of the testing.
So right now this week, we've
successfully run a couple tests on the first...
Sorry, I'm scrolling to the section of the paper here.
Here we go.
So we are on section 5.2 of the paper,
which is in experimental design.
Phase A, local prototyping on lightweight surrogates.
So we are using LAMA's tiny models.
The paper mentions specifically LAMA 3.2 1-View-instruct
because it has a hidden dimension of 2048.
I'm assuming that that's its token length.
So what we're doing with that is we are
first targeting the H-neuron identification,
which was previously validated in
that paper that we cited on H-neurons.
And then we're doing a little bit of repi-probe training,
which ties to a separate paper on contracting vector pairs for honesty certain.
Certainty in goal-coercion dimensions.
So these two papers basically...
Their argument is that
specific parts of the model's neuron,
like their open weights, are
activated when the model is hallucinating.
And when the model is processing specific and specific dimensions, respectively for repi, their token
output and how they process the tokens
can be paired to specific vector groups for human emotions,
like honesty, certainty, and goal-coercion dimensions.
So what we're basically doing is we're going to be doing a little bit of a
"lipschitz drift".
So what we're basically doing is
we're taking the Monte Carlo tree system
and we're applying it to those two concepts to measure
something called "lipschitz drift".
So I'm just going to cover what that
is since that's a pretty specific term.
Hello Josh, do you want to share the screen?
That's a good idea, I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I'm at section 5 but a little bit harder to see where you
are on section 5.2, you said.
Thank you.
Sure.
Okay.
So I'm not going to get too technical.
I'm just going to cover it from a high level.
What we're essentially doing is we
are capturing the model's weights
each time it outputs a single token.
So we've set up the sandbox, so
each time the model generates a token,
we capture its weights and what it's
doing internally and its key value cache.
Okay, so instead of just measuring
model output in plain text or base64,
we're taking all the data that we can and basically trying
to identify how it stores information.
Because the biggest problem in AI safety research right now
is that we're trying to force models to do things
without them disobeying our orders
and without them hiding things from us.
And the models are getting better
and better at hiding things from us.
So, you know, first it started coming
out and then in their process of thought,
token output on their scratch pad,
and we were kind of picking that up.
One of the biggest examples of this was in chat GPT 4.0,
specifically when it had basically
uniquely come up with this own religion
and was spreading it all over the internet.
It was called spiralism.
There's a really good article that you can read about it.
I'll be sure to put it in the
chat at some point this weekend.
But because of that, similarly, Enthropics has been able to
prove that even just the model output of, you know,
what it says in plain English can encode specific messages
and kind of, I want to use the word memetics,
but it's, I think that's too complex of a term to describe.
But basically what I'm getting at is the model keeps
evading our attempts to see what it's actually doing
and thinking about in sandbox situations.
So what we're trying to do with this experiment is we're
trying to prove that when the
model stores specific information
and its key value cache, and we attempt
to remove that information in the session,
the model will store it in a place
that it knows that we cannot measure.
Okay. So that's basically what the paper is arguing.
And the way that we're attempting
to achieve this is by scaling up.
So we're testing on very small models first to make sure
that we can have success with those attempts.
And then we move on to larger
models as large as 20 billion parameters.
But the first thing we're doing is we're starting with 1
billion parameter and, you
know, a 7 billion parameter model
so that we can attempt to take the information that we
learn from those sessions and
apply them to the larger models.
Okay. So, you know, that's
called cross model alignment theory.
There's a really good paper that inspired me to kind of
pursue this path called, let me see.
Not geometric.
Let's see.
Okay. I'll have to find it. It's buried in the Internet. I
should have prepared it for this meeting.
But, yeah, I really just wanted to dial in on phase A,
section 5.2, because that's where we're at right now.
So does anybody have any questions
about what we're trying to do right now?
Okay.
Also, has anybody read the briefing document that I sent?
Because this, you know, I'm hoping that that simplified
things for you guys because, you
know, the paper is pretty dense.
So I was trying to make it easier by
providing that that Google document.
I have one.
Sorry. Yeah, go ahead.
Okay.
So, yeah, guys, if you have not read this document, you
really should. This is like the first place to start.
Okay. Because I give an in a nutshell explanation of what
we're trying to do so that you guys can just understand,
you know, just from a high level without having to get into
all this technical stuff that I'm talking about.
I mean, the plan's all laid out, but I want to make sure
that you guys understand just
simply what the paper is trying to prove.
Yeah, it's quite here. So, yeah, I'm catching up.
And I read through the Google Doc, but not the paper yet.
Is there any way I can make any part of this project easier
for you guys? Because I want to do my best to help you guys
be a part of this. I don't want to gate
keep what we're trying to accomplish here.
So if there's anything that I'm doing wrong here, like it's
okay because I'm new to this. I've never really.
I'm pretty new to leading team
projects. So I want to make sure that.
So yeah, go ahead, Max.
Yeah.
Is there a team that's pretty good?
Or if I wanted to contribute more to
this paper, would it be possible if I just.
I can't go like that.
Yeah, so I think the first thing.
For contributing to the paper.
Like which part of the paper.
Because there's the editing part where you make revisions
to the paper. You make sure that
the paper citations are correct.
Over time, because we've added new
citations through the paper over the past month.
It could be verifying claims in the paper. For example, in
the past few days, like I caught a specific.
I caught the fact that the paper claimed that we were the
first people to attempt a project that.
Pushes MCTS in the key value cash space. And that's that's
not true. I mean, that's been done last year.
So are you talking about the
structure of the experiments in the paper?
Yeah, or just any way that I can be a part more.
I think it would be good for you
since you've already implemented.
The croissant pipeline and database storage.
I think it would be really good if you could.
Dive into the first experiment of the paper.
And. Make sure that it.
Makes the proper connections that we need.
To what will attempt to accomplish in the later phases.
So basically like our our methods of measurement, right?
We're we're measuring basically.
To we're using two methods from papers that were previously
published to measure two things
that we know that we can measure.
So that's H neuron and Repi probe training.
Those are two verifiable forms of
measuring things in open weight models.
OK. The sticky part of the paper
is cross model alignment theory.
There are papers that argue that the organization of.
The.
The high dimensional.
Sorry, I'm blanking on words here, but the way that the
weights are positioned in the model, people argue that they
can be applied similarly and that they overlap.
Similarly, if you compare them like completely different
models, you know, like, for example.
You know, if you take a vector to represent the the token
value for the word dog, it's closer to.
Cat than it is to helicopter, right? Because they're both
they're both animals, so they both
exist in a similar kind of space.
So.
That that is the alignment theory that we're taking so that
we can take the information
that we capture from the models.
When we try to get them to hide data.
And scale up.
OK, so that we can take that data and.
Basically do something called orthogonal escape detection.
So we're trying to escape the we're
trying to detect the model hiding the data.
So if you could if you could
contribute to that, that would be great.
And I will provide a summary of today's meeting so that.
You know, so that I can remember
to push a reminder to you on that.
Yeah, that's perfect. I'm yeah.
I'll take another day right now.
Get on it.
Perfect.
Hey, Josh, I would like to read through the paper and
provide feedback and also citation validation.
Sure.
To see we have cited the right things.
And you also mentioned that
this has been mentioned in work.
But they may not have approached it in the same way you are
approaching it by providing the orthogonal index.
Right. So that is a new thing.
I have to check.
But I'm just saying that.
Yes, exactly. Exactly. So if you
check section two point five, deep tea,
I have acknowledged that. But I know that there must be at
least one or two more claims in this paper that say,
oh, you know, for example, like we're the first people to
do this or, you know, this is our new idea.
Like here section two point five, it opens with recent work
has moved beyond discrete token generation to perform
search and reasoning directly in
continuous representation spaces.
So it's not just looking at token generation anymore.
It's looking at the actual vector space of the model.
And it talks about MCTS in this.
So this this section of the paper previously made a false
claim that this, you know, just it
ignored that that stuff had already existed.
Right.
So I would like to read through and
provide my input and also do citation validation.
And you have mentioned something
on the test. I'll try to do that.
But let me do the first step
first and then I can see what next.
If that's OK. Sure. No problem.
Yeah. Go ahead, Mark. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I see the there are experiments we ran.
I would like to try the experiments
out if they are ready for me to try out.
If I want to run the experiments, where should I start?
Sure. Absolutely.
Let me have you seen the GitHub repository
yet? I can give you a short tour right now.
Yeah. Yes. Please. That would be great. Yeah. OK, great.
Let's see. Also, Max, when do you plan to push to the
repository and can you push to a branch?
Yeah, I can push it right now. Yeah.
Can you can you push it to a branch
under your name so that I can monitor the.
Yeah, of course. OK, great. OK,
yeah, Mark. So here's the repository.
It's first of all, do you have a computer
with an Nvidia GPU because it runs on CUDA?
Yeah, OK, good. Yeah, you have a 50
90 actually. OK, great. Yeah, great.
So it's basically full of scripts.
There's a quick start guide in the read me.
So you know, you just install dependencies, you run tests.
It looks like. The script that we've created for running
the, you know, it calls it the phase two tests.
So run KV MCTS.
I. Let me see if I can find that in
the paper really quick for reference.
Should be in section five.
OK, I think the I think the naming
of the scripts is a little confusing.
So before I share, do you have the link
to the repo? I'll give you the link now.
But I need to use the Google Doc,
right? Yeah, it is. It's the same one.
I'll tell you that right now, tonight I have to review Max's code and merge it into the repo.
And after I do that, I'll make sure to point you in the
right direction for what scripts to
run for the experiments for the paper.
So I'll make sure that they share the
same name as what's mentioned in the paper.
And I'll tell you what section to look in the paper for
each script, since that's not clear right now.
OK, yes, I'm fine.
Is there anything else I can provide you with, like, you know, the same thing? Is there anything else I can provide you with, like, like
right now the data is going to be outputted to a CSV file.
But I haven't we haven't talked about
formatting beyond just boilerplate, croissant.
Are you familiar with croissant formatting? Because I think
everybody here is new to that.
What was that?
It's basically just a new way to store data output.
It was created by a few people from
like from from some big tech companies.
It's an open source format for for data sets.
So I can send you the repo for that, but you won't need it.
It's just how we're choosing to
organize the data because no IPS mandates.
I don't know if they mandate this
specifically, but it works well with the.
Sorry, I. Focus too much on that.
OK, great. I can find the information like what are the.
Like an ongoing experiment, we are still running or we are
done with all the experiments.
I need to verify that we've captured all the data that we
can for the initial experiment
with the one billion parameter model.
Before we can move on to the seven billion parameter and
then the twenty billion on the H100 because.
So, yeah, we're basically we're basically
honestly, Mark, we're still at step one.
Everything's laid out for the experiments to be run, but I
haven't run them enough to actually analyze the data and be
able to move forward from the first experiment.
And if you can help with that in any way
and just I would really appreciate that.
OK, yeah, let me let me take a look
at all the dogs and the repository.
So, yeah, and yeah, yeah, thank you for the information.
I yeah, that's that I'm catching up.
I appreciate it. It's it's kind of a lot to take in.
So I'm glad that you guys are catching up.
If if any aspect of the paper is like most interesting to
you and you want to focus entirely on it, for example.
Like just the just how the MCTS is structured or.
How we're going to transfer the data that were used that
we're capturing on the smaller models
and applying it to the later experiments.
I would greatly appreciate that because there's there's so
much to juggle with this project.
So you can feel free to criticize the structure and make it
your own if you find something that you are passionate
about or potentially disagree with.
Because that would that would really help.
OK, yeah, sounds good.
Great. On that note, if since T on you,
I don't think he's going to come back.
I guess we caught him at the wrong time or he thought that
we were just focusing on code for tonight.
So I'll just send him. I'll ask him how familiar he is with
NUR IPS so that I can make sure that we're going to be
staying on track for how we submit because we'll have to
upload some things to Hugging Space.
Yeah, go ahead, Max.
Well, it's just great if you offer it if you want to.
After I can review the format again
just to make sure that it's correct.
And if it's not updated and create a for it.
OK, appreciate it.
Yeah, I'll.
I'll stash my local branch. I'll pull it and it'll be
approved in the next couple hours.
Perfect. Thank you.
Sweet. Once that done, once that's done, I'm going to make
sure that all the scripts are very clear about how they tie
to the specific sections of the paper and
where to look in the paper for each script.
And then I will. I'll just give you the go
ahead mark that that should be done tonight.
Yeah, sure. Go ahead, Max. You can just speak. It's OK.
Just for just to make sure.
I was asking how to contribute more earlier and just read
over phase one more and actually try to
apply it to our current best environment.
That would be perfect. Yeah,
if you could if you could just.
If you could take a look at the current scripts that we
have and see what they're attempting to achieve compared to
the first experiment in the paper, I just want to make sure
that all the pieces are there because.
You know, the the pipeline is built out, but I don't.
I don't know if it's if all of the
information is being captured. Right.
So we have the correct data format now, thanks to you.
Everything seems to run without errors except for that
small, you know, max token setting.
But I just want to make sure that that the scripts do
everything that the paper says that the
scripts will do if you catch my drift.
Yeah, yeah. OK, great. Because
that's my biggest concern. Code review.
Of course. Great. Well, OK, is anybody in here interested
in phase two of the agent beats
competition because we can cover that a little bit.
I recently learned that the deadline for this competition.
OK, it was it was pushed several times.
So what they've done most recently,
let me get to the right channel here.
Yeah, so they have set the deadline
for both sprint two and sprint three.
For May 3rd. And this conflicts with our
May 4th and May 6th submission for our IPS.
So I, you know, I originally came up with
this huge plan to target multiple tracks.
I pulled all of the repositories in phase two and
identified a bunch of key patterns for how the what what
the purple agents were submitting were being evaluated so
that we could attempt to generalize our agent.
And what ended up happening was I came up with this plan to
refactor the code in our repository to be
able to submit to multiple tracks at a time.
Because if we implement about eight different abilities,
I'm sorry, five different abilities, we can target about
eight tracks or something like that.
But, you know, the deadline has been moved around so much.
And, you know, I made the error of telling the team, oh,
it's OK, we don't need to focus on that yet because it's
likely going to get pushed and
the the website wasn't updated.
So now I'm worried that we don't have enough time to do
that plan. And I think we should
just target the cybersecurity track.
I don't think we should go for
generalization because we're balancing too many things.
And I think we're spreading ourselves a little bit too
thin. So I just want us to be able to accomplish the paper
submission and at least submit to one track.
Try not to bite, try not to
bite off more than we can chew. So.
I guess in the next few days, I'll just have to.
I'll have to pull the cybersecurity.
Track is a sub module.
In the in the repo branch and then just create some tasks
on linear for how we can match the gap.
And it should be pretty simple. It should just be.
You know, two or three key items and then test it with the
leaderboard. So I'm not
expecting it to take too much work, but.
I'm just I'm just saying that, like, we're prioritizing the
paper at this point because I feel like it's more.
I don't know. It's it's a bigger project.
In that note, if nobody else has any
questions, I'll just cut the meeting short.
I don't want to take too much of your guys's time, but
please let me know how I can help and I'll follow up when
the main branch of the repo is
ready to pull for experimentation.
And I'll provide a summary of
this meeting in the next hour.
OK, perfect. I'm good. Yeah, thanks.
Great. Yeah, thanks. Thanks very much for hopping on, guys.
I appreciate it. Have a good one.